Register of the Russia. Posol'stvo (France) Records, 1916-1924
Hoover Institution Archives
- SUBJECT FILE, 1916-1924 (Box 13-36)
  - Divorces among Russians (Folder 16)
  - Economic Conference in the Crimea, Autumn, 1920 (Folder 17)
  - Estonia (Folder 18)
  - European War, peace negotiations, 1914-1918 (Folder 19)
  - Extraordinary Delegation from the Population of the Zabaikai and Amur Regions, Port Arthur, April 1921 (Folder 20)
  - Finland
    - General (Folder 21)
    - Boundaries (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Information on Russia, 1921-1923 (Folder 2)
    - Political parties and press (Folder 3)
    - Relations with Russia (Folder 4)
    - Russian Army supply, 1919 (Folder 5)
    - Russian refugees (Folder 6)
  - France
    - General (Folder 7)
    - Relations with Soviet Russia (Folder 8)
  - Galicia, Carpathians, Bucovina (Folder 9-10)
  - Genoa Conference, 1922 (Folder 11)
  - Genoa Conference, 1922 (Box 17, Folder 1-5)
  - Germany
    - General (Folder 6)
    - Relations with Soviet Russia, 1919 (Folder 7)
  - Great Britain
    - General (Folder 8)
    - Relations with Soviet Russia, 1922 (Folder 9)
  - Great Britain and Ireland (Folder 10)
  - Greece (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Hague Conference, 1922 (Folder 2)
  - Holland, trade relations with Soviet Russia, 1922-1923 (Folder 3)
  - International Commission for the Study of the Situation in Russia (Folder 4)
  - International Commission of Relief to Russia, 1921 (Folder 5)
  - International law (Folder 6)
  - Italy
    - Coal mining crisis, 1919 (Folder 7)
    - Reports from Rome dealing with relations with Soviet Russia, trial of communists, Russian refugees, the Pope, etc., 1923 (Folder 8)
  - Iudenich, General, interview with, April 18, 1919 (Folder 9)
  - Japan. Reports from Tokyo dealing with trade relations with Soviet Russia, the earthquake, financial affairs, etc., 1923 (Folder 10)
  - Kolchak, Admiral (Folder 11)
  - Kostevich, Colonel (Folder 12)
  - League of Nations
    - Financial and economic role, 1918-1919 (Folder 13)
    - Russian questions, 1923 (Folder 14)
    - Soviet Russian economy, 1924 (Folder 15)
  - Manchuria (Folder 16)
  - Military law, 1919 (Folder 17)
  - Monarchists, Russian (Folder 18)
  - Montenegro, 1920 (Folder 19)
  - Nansen, Dr. (Folder 20)
  - Norway. Trade relations with Soviet Russia, 1923 (Folder 21)
  - Novoe Vremia, 1922 (Folder 22)
  - Office of Documentation and Information on Russia (Paris), Bulletin No., 16, September 1918 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Paris Peace Conference, 1919
    - General (Folder 2)
    - Aland Islands (Folder 3)
    - Armenian Delegation (Folder 4)
    - Balkan countries (Folder 5)
    - Korean Delegation (Folder 6)
    - Norway, annexation of Spitzberg (Folder 7)
    - Pan-Islamism (Folder 8)
    - Russia
      - General (Folder 9)
      - Financial and economic questions (Folder 10)
      - Russian Commission for the Establishment of Peace (Folder 11)
    - Supreme Economic Council (Folder 12)
    - Syndicalism (Folder 13)
  - Passports and visas (Folder 14)
  - People's Freedom Party (Partiia Narodaoi Svobody) (Box 20, Folder 1-2)
  - Persia
    - General, 1920-1921 (Folder 3)
    - Persian-Soviet agreement, 1921 (Folder 4)
  - Poland
    - General (Folder 5)
    - Jews in (Folder 6)
  - Prisoners of war, Russian (Folder 7)
  - Red Cross, International Committee, Joint Council (Folder 8)
  - Refugees, Russian (Folder 9)
  - Russia
    - Bolshevik rule (Folder 10)
      - General (Folder 11)
      - General (Box 21, Folder 1-7)
      - General (Box 22, Folder 1-6)
      - Agents abroad (Folder 7)
      - Concessions, 1919 (Folder 8)
      - Employment (Folder 9)
      - Exchange of prisoners, 1920 (Folder 10)
      - Military situation, 1919 (Folder 11)
      - Press (Box 23, Folder 1)
      - Relations with the Allies, 1920 (Folder 2)
      - Relations with Germany (Folder 3)
    - Civil War
      - General (Folder 4-7)
      - Agrarian question (Folder 8)
      - Allied Intervention
        - General (Folder 9-10)
        - American Expeditionary Forces (Box 24, Folder 1)
        - Finnish military operations (Folder 2)
        - French mission (Folder 3)
        - Great Britain (Folder 4)
        - Japan (Folder 5)
        - Poole, F. S., General (Folder 6)
      - Anti-bolshevik propaganda (Folder 7)
      - Baltic Fleet (Folder 8)
      - Bolshevic atrocities (Folder 9)
      - Bulletins on military operations of the Armed Forces of South Russia, 1919-1920 (Folder 10-13)
      - Caucasus (Box 25, Folder 1-2)
      - Commerce and industry (Folder 3)
      - Cossack revolt, Upper Don area, 1919 (Folder 4)
      - Crimea (Folder 5)
      - Economy and economic reconstruction (Folder 6-8)
      - Far East (Folder 9)
      - Far East (Box 26, Folder 1)
      - Finances and supplies (Folder 2)
      - Foreign trade (Folder 3)
      - Northern region (Folder 4-7)
      - Northwestern region and Baltic states (Folder 8)
      - Peasant uprisings (Folder 9)
      - Petrograd (Folder 10)
      - Petrograd and Moscow (Folder 11)
      - Red Army, 1919-1921 (Folder 12)
      - Siberia
        - General (Box 27, Folder 1)
        - Czech Legion (Folder 2)
        - Omsk Government (Folder 3)
        - Priamur and Primor'e regions (Folder 4)
        - Provisional Government (Folder 5-6)
        - Provisional Priamur Government (Folder 7)
      - Southern region
        - General (Folder 8-9)
        - Don and Kuban Republics (Box 28, Folder 1)
        - Ekaterinodar, National Center, May 16, 1919 (Folder 2)
        - Military Supply (Folder 3)
        - Odessa (Folder 4)
        - Propaganda section bulletins, 1919-1920 (Folder 5)
        - Wrangel's Army, 1921 (Folder 6)
      - Special Commission to Investigate Bolshevik Crimes (Commission Speciale d'Instruction sur les Crimes des Bolcheviks) (Folder 7)
      - Special Commission to Investigate Bolshevik Crimes (Osobaia Komissiia po Razsledovaniiu Zlodeianii Bolshevikov) (Folder 8-9)
      - Ukraine
        - General (Folder 10)
        - General (Box 29, Folder 1-3)
        - Pogroms, 1918 (Folder 4)
        - Representatives abroad, 1919 (Folder 5)
      - Volunteer Army (Folder 6)
      - Western region (Folder 7-8)
      - White Armies
        - General (Folder 9)
        - Supply (Box 30, Folder 1-4)
    - Economy, Import and Industrial Bank, Kiev (Folder 5)
    - Excerpts from the Soviet press, 1922 (Folder 6)
    - Famine, 1921 (Folder 7)
    - Novorossiia (Folder 8)
    - People's Commissariat of Foreign Affairs
      - Publication of secret treaties, 1918 (Folder 9)
      - Regulations for obtaining entry visas, January 1918 (Folder 10)
    - Politics and government, 1918-1922 (Folder 11-13)
    - Politics and government, 1918-1924 (Box 31, Folder 1-2)
    - Railroads, delegation of the Council of Private Railroads of Russia to Paris, February 1921 (Folder 3)
    - Relations with the Allies (Folder 4)
    - Relief organizations
      - All-Russian Committee of Relief to the Starving (Folder 5)
      - Religion and state, 1923 (Folder 6)
      - Revolution
        - General (Folder 7)
        - Political Parties (Folder 8)
      - Unified Committee of Russian Relief Organizations to the Starving (Folder 9)
      - World War I economy (Folder 10)
  - Russian Army abroad
    - General (Folder 11)
    - France (Folder 12)
    - France (Box 32, Folder 1-3)
    - Military Agent, 1919 (Folder 4)
    - Repatriation of POW's (Folder 5)
    - Requisitions (Folder 6)
    - Salonica front, 1918 (Folder 7)
  - Russian-Asiatic Bank (Paris) (Folder 8)
  - Russian emigre organizations and political parties (Folder 9-11)
  - Russian emigre organizations and political parties (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Russian Financial, Industrial and Commercial Union (Paris) (Folder 2-3)
  - Russian Imperial Family (Folder 4)
  - Russian Information Office (Paris), Bulletins, 1918-1919, 1922 (Folder 5)
  - Russian Military Agents, instructions, 1912 (Folder 6)
  - Russian Ministries of Ways and Communications abroad, representatives, 1919-1920 (Folder 7)
  - Russian Mission in China, 1917-1920 (Folder 8)
  - Russian National Union (Russkii Natsional'nyi Soiuz), 1921-1923 (Folder 9-10)
  - Russian Naval Agent (Paris), 1919 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Russian Navy abroad (Folder 2)
  - Russian Orthodox Church abroad (Folder 3)
  - Russian press and propaganda abroad (Folder 4)
  - Russian Red Cross (Folder 5-6)
  - Russian Scientific Institute (Berlin), Section for the Study of Modern Russian Culture, undated (Folder 7)
  - Russian Telegraph Agency in Poland ("Russpress") (Folder 8)
  - Russian Zemstvo-Municipal Relief Committee to Russian Citizens Abroad (Rossiiskii Zemsko-Gorodskoi Komitet Pomoshchi Rossiiskim Grazhdanan Zagranitsei), 1921-1923 (Folder 9-10)
  - Russkaia Gazeta (Paris), 1923 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Sack, A. J., "Russia in the Limelight," undated (Folder 2)
  - Schaeck, Ivan de, memoirs on the Russian Revolution and Civil War (in French), Kislovodsk, 1919 (Folder 3)
  - Semenov, Ataman (Folder 4)
  - Serbia, 1920-1921, 1923 (Folder 5)
  - Shcherbachev, General "Brief Survey of Military Operations of the Volunteer, Caucasus, Azovsko-Crimean and Don Armies from " (in Russian), January 15 to February 14, 1919 (Folder 6)
  - Siberia (Folder 7)
  - Socialist-revolutionaries (Folder 8)
  - Spargo, John
    - "A Memorandum on Trade With Soviet Russia,", January 1921 (Folder 9)
    - "The Problem of Trading With Soviet Russia,", January 1921 (Folder 10)
  - Sukin, I. I., memoirs (in Russian) on the Omsk Government (Folder 11)
  - Switzerland (Folder 12)
  - Telegrams, codes, etc. (Folder 13)
  - Tikhon, Patriarch (Folder 14)
  - Turkey
    - General (Folder 15-16)
    - Peace negotiations, 1923 (Box 36, Folder 1-2)
    - Russian material interests in (Folder 3)
    - Russian refugees, 1922 (Folder 4)
  - Ukraine
    - General (Folder 5)
    - Commerce, finances, industry, 1918 (Folder 6)
    - Pogroms against Jews, 1919 (Folder 7)
    - Relations with Poland, 1920 (Folder 8)
  - Ukrainian National Committee (Paris) (Folder 9)
  - Ungern-Shternberg, Baron (Folder 10)
  - U.S.A., 1919 (Folder 11)
  - Vitaly, Archmandrite (Folder 12)
  - Volkovitskii, Iu., report on Siberian railroads and military events, Paris, May 1918 (Folder 13)
  - Wahl, General de, 1921 (Folder 14)
- MISCELLANY (Box 36-37)
  Miscellaneous correspondence, memoranda, printed matter, etc.
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, memoranda, printed matter, etc. (Box 36, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, memoranda, printed matter, etc. (Box 37, Folder 1-3)